<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project 3</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Project 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Basics</title>
      <link>/blog/pythonbasicsblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pythonbasicsblog/</guid>
      <description>Python Basics When it comes to R versus Python, both languages can be quite useful. Compared to R, Python appears sleeker, operates faster, and its libraries can be a bit more difficult to run. In addition, Python documentation is limited but this language still remains more popular than R. The core Python data science stack includes Matplotlib, Numpy, and Jupyter among others. While Python can be used with Jupyterhub on the educcomp severs, it can also be used in R Studio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 22:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1: Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>library(readr) data1 &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;framingham.csv&amp;quot;) library(readr) data2 &amp;lt;- read_delim(&amp;quot;cardio_train.csv&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;;&amp;quot;, escape_double = FALSE, trim_ws = TRUE) library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(formatR) library(tidyverse) Sabrina Strausser sas6824 0. Introduction Since I am interested in going into the medical field, I wanted to work with some datasets related to health. I chose my two datasets because both study the effects of smoking, BMI, gender, and age on blood pressure. The shared variables between the two datasets include smoking, BMI, age, gender, and blood pressure, while the unshared variables include total cholesterol, glucose, diabetes, and heart rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2: Modeling</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>library(readr) data1 &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;quot;framingham.csv&amp;quot;) library(readr) data2 &amp;lt;- read_delim(&amp;quot;cardio_train.csv&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;;&amp;quot;, escape_double = FALSE, trim_ws = TRUE) library(dplyr) library(ggplot2) library(formatR) library(tidyverse) library(mvtnorm) library(lmtest) library(sandwich) Sabrina Strausser sas6824 0. For this project, I wanted to use my dataset from my first project, which presents data on diabetic and nondiabetic individuals. For each person, their age, BMI, gender, total cholesterol (“totChol”), heart rate (“heartRate”), whether they are a smoker or not (“currentSmoker”), glucose level (“glucose”), diabetic state (“diabetes”), systolic blood pressure (“sysBP”), and diastolic blood pressure (“diaBP”) has been recorded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>  Project 1 Project 2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/p3resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/p3resume/</guid>
      <description>Sabrina Strausser
Address 2400 Nueces St Apartment #1341 Austin, Texas 78705
Phone 936-520-2977
Email sabrina.strausser@gmail.com
Education
2020 Bachelor of Science, Biology The University of Texas, Austin, TX
 Relevant coursework: - Biology - Biochemistry - General Chemistry - Organic Chemistry - Physics - Calculus - Genetics - Human Genetics - Peer mentor for Gene Detectives Course (Spring Semester 2017) - Peer mentor for Introduction to Computational Biology Course (Fall Semester 2017)  Medical and Research Experience</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>